You wouldn't want to meet these pinheads in an alley.
Kingpin is a comedy film directed by Bobby Farrelly.
After bowler Roy Munson swindles the wrong crowd and is left with a
hook for a hand, he settles into impoverished obscurity.
That is, until he uncovers the next big thing: an Amish kid named Ishmael.
So, the corrupt and the hopelessly naive hit the circuit
intent on settling an old score with Big Ern.
Roy Munson, played by Woody Harrelson.
Ishmael Boorg, played by Randy Quaid.
Claudia, played by Vanessa Angel.
Ernie McCracken, played by Bill Murray.
The Gambler, played by Chris Elliott.
Mr. Boorg, played by William Jordan.
Kingpin is a 1996 American sports comedy film directed by Peter and
Bobby Farrelly and written by Barry Fanaro and Mort Nathan.
Starring Woody Harrelson, Randy Quaid, Vanessa Angel and Bill Murray, it tells the story of an alcoholic
ex-professional bowler (Harrelson) who becomes the manager for a promising Amish talent (Quaid).
It was filmed in and around Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, as a
stand-in for Scranton, Amish country, and Reno, Nevada.
The film was produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, Motion Picture Corporation of America
and Rysher Entertainment and released by MGM/UA Distribution Co.
on July 26, 1996, with a budget of $25 million.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $32.2 million.
The film explores themes of sports, stripper,
handicap, sexual favor, star spangled banner.
The tone is lighthearted.